International Fur and Leather Workers Union Records 5676
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Canada - Toronto Fur Workers Union Joint Board, 1924-1936 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  correspondence between M. Kaufman, Frank Currie and others, 1924, re plans for Canadian Conference and a meeting where Mrs. Warashsky explained about politics and the New York Joint Board; re Gold, Manager of the New York Joint Board, speaking at a meeting of Local 35; re "Peace and Unity Movement," 1927; Joint Board financial difficulties; Gold speaking before a TEUL meeting; correspondence and resoluiton re New York situation, 1927; lists of members; and financial.
- Canada - Toronto Fur Workers Union Joint Board, 1938 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  16 p. report by Joint Board, entitled "Corruption Condemned"; routine and financial.
- Canada - Toronto Fur Workers Union Joint Board, 1939 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  January-August; routine and financial.
- Canada - Toronto Fur Workers Union Joint Board, 1939 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  September-December; routine and financial.
- Canada - Toronto Fur Workers Union Joint Board, 1940 (Box 28, Folder 15)
- Canada - Toronto Fur Workers Union Joint Board, 1941 (Box 28, Folder 16)
- Canada - Toronto Fur Workers Union Joint Board, 1942 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  January-July; routine and financial.
- Canada - Toronto Fur Workers Union Joint Board, 1942 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  August-December; routine and financial.
- Canada - Toronto Fur Workers Union Joint Board, 1944-1945 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  letter from Gold to Fred Collins, organizer for Joint Board - Gold said, "Toronto locals never had any leadership.... leaders ... until 1938 were either incompetent or dishonest"; letter from Collins to Gold detailing problems with locals within the Joint Board, 4 p.; negotiation situation; report on Ottawa organizing (letter from Collins); and routine.
- Canada - Toronto Fur Workers Union Joint Board, 1947-1955 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  Joint Board newsletter, No. 1 and 2, 1947; routine correspondence; broadsides re merger with Meat Cutters.
- Canada - Toronto Fur Workers Union Joint Board (Box 28, Folder 21)
  routine re merger; copy of agreement.
- Canada - Vancouver Joint Board, 1953-1954 (Box 28, Folder 22)
- Canada - Winnipeg Joint Board, 1954-1955 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  agreement; correspondence re organizing in Winnipeg.
- New York - Fur Dressers and Dyers Joint Board, 1938 (Box 28, Folder 24)
- New York - Fur Dressers and Dyers Joint Board, 1939 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  Souvenir Journal; routine correspondence and financial.
- New York - Fur Dressers and Dyers Joint Board, 1940-1941 (Box 28, Folder 26)
- New York - Fur Dressers and Dyers Joint Board, 1942 (Box 28, Folder 27)
- New York - Fur Dressers and Dyers Joint Board, 1945-1947 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  correspondence between Sam Burt, Manager, and Ben Gold re hourly rate of pay in locals; politically backing Henry A. Wallace; and routine.
- New York - Fur Dressers and Dyers Joint Board, 1954 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  3 p. letter from Gold addressing the Annual Shop Chairmen's Conference; form letters; bulletins; 2 p. minutes of membership meeting of Local 165 re suspension of local President and work stoppage; re problems and negotiations between Hollander Co. and members of Local 135, Middletown; broadsides; constitution of the Joint Board, undated.
- New York - Furriers Joint Council, 1938 (Box 28, Folder 30)
- New York - Furriers Joint Council, 1939 (Box 28, Folder 31)
- New York - Furriers Joint Council, 1940 (Box 28, Folder 32)
  broadside; lists of members; routine and financial.
- New York - Furriers Joint Council, 1942-1944 (Box 28, Folder 33)
  ballots, lists, routine and financial.
- New York - Furriers Joint Council, 1942-1944 (Box 28, Folder 34)
  broadsides; routine and financial.
- New York - Furriers Joint Council, 1945 (Box 28, Folder 35)
  release re contract between Joint Council and Greater New York Retail Furriers Association; broadsides; 8 p. mss. "An Important Declaration to All Fur Workers by the Shop Chairmen and Active Rank and File"; form letters; routine; and misc.
- New York - Furriers Joint Council, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 36)
  broadside re May Day and other misc.; complaints from members re union members working in non-union shops; 3 p. letter, 6/28/47, to Potash Manager from Gold re Taft-Hartley Act; correspondence re various agreements; 3 p. mss., undated, re Taft-Hartley Act.
- New York - Furriers Joint Council, 1954 (Box 28, Folder 37)
  3 p. letter from Gold to Louis Loeb, Impartial Chairman, 1/7/54, re the decision for a reduction of 15% in rate of pay and why the union will not accept the decision and Loeb's reply; further correspondence with others re reduction of wages; correspondence re various complaints of members and shop owners; and routine.
- New York - Furriers Joint Council Miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  broadsides; issues of Furriers Joint Council Bulletin; issues of "News from the Trial of President Gold"; completed "survey of unemployed workers"; and other misc.
- New York - Furriers Joint Council (Box 29, Folder 2)
  misc. broadsides; agreement; issue of Welfare Department Bulletin; 2 p. mss. re Communist attack.
- New York - Furriers Union, Joint Board, 1923 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  correspondence re protesting method of elections of Local 15; objections of certain people being placed on ballots for Local 15; broadside; and misc.
- New York - Furriers Union, Joint Board, 1923 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  No. 2, 1923 Furriers Bulletin, published by the Trade Union Educational League, Furriers Section; remaining all untranslated Yiddish.
- New York - Furriers Union, Joint Board, 1924 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  January-August; copies of letters between attorney Joseph Brodsky and Joint Board re various legal problems and charges; and routine.
- New York - Furriers Union, Joint Board, 1924 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  September-December; additional copies of legal correspondence; 5 p. mss. re special meeting to investigate charges against Herman Gold for selling union books; broadsides.
- New York - Furriers Union, Joint Board, 1925 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  January-April; "Official Statement of the General Executive Board of the International Regarding the Present Relations Between the New York Manufacturers and the New York Joint Board," 3 p.; correspondence re grievances and appeals; "To the Members of Our New York Local 1, 5, 10 and 15," 4 p. memo re dishonest practice of admitting new members.
- New York - Furriers Union, Joint Board, 1925 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  May-July; correspondence re the removal of 3rd Vice-President Drownstein from office for misconduct; 2 p., Special Joint Board Meeting - Thursday, May 21 re removal of Abraham Rosenthal from office; 2 p. appeal by Rosenthal; resolution re member Harry Cohn assaulted at a meeting of the Joint Board; telegram re Joint Board withdrawing all their money from the International; 4 p. minutes of Local 5, July 2, 1925; broadsides; letter from President and International to Joint Board re the Joint Board attempting to prevent members of Local 5 from holding a meeting; letter re local 15 members being denied the right to attend a meeting; re illegal meetings and elections.
- New York - Furriers Union, Joint Board, 1925 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  August-December; broadsides; "To All Our Local Unions and Friendly Labor Organizations," from Morris Kaufman, President, 8 p., 9/8/25, re the Joint Board's tactics during the general strike of the Montreal Fur Workers; continued correspondence re problems between Joint Board and International; revoking charter of Local 51; "Statement by A. Rosenthal, Secretary-Treasurer of Joint Board Furriers Union for 12 Years", undated; other undated and misc.
- New York - Furriers Union, Joint Board, 1926 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  January-June; publication entitled "Our Demands" by B. Gold, Manager, Joint Board, re demands during negotiations of new agreement with Fur Manufacturers Association; 12 p. re charges against members of Joint Board by the International re a conspiracy for the purpose of obtaining control of all funds belonging to the Joint Board; letter from General President Schactman to Gold, 4/14/26, re "I am warning you that I will take all legal measures to safe-guard the life, liberty and welfare of every member of our union.... I will hold you and your entire committee as a body and individually responsible for every act that may occur in the future"; 2 p. appeal from Schactman re assistance for New York striking members; draft copies of editorials re the settlement of the strike.
- New York - Furriers Union, Joint Board, 1926 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  July-September; correspondence from Local 15 re resolution against Chicago Local 45 expelling members; letter, 8/5/26 from Gold to Schactman about letter explaining the investigation that the Joint Board received from AFL, and Gold questioning the purpose; letter from Gold to I. Wohl, Secretary of the International re treatment of scabs; 5 p. draft of editorial by Gold, "The Furrier Strike: Its Conclusion and Its Significance"; additional correspondence re the investigation by the AFL Committee.
- New York - Furriers Union, Joint Board, 1926 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  October-December; 2 p. re excerpts from Freiheit articles; to Wohl from Gold re the publication of The Fur Worker; form letters re charges against President Schactman; 4 p., 11/4/26, to M. Woll from Schactman(?) re problems between International and Joint Board; 3 p. report to Wohl from Vice-President A. Gross re Chicago settlement and protesting Schactman's conduct for being neutral during negotiations; other correspondence re Fur Worker articles against the Joint Board; list of officers of the Joint Board; broadside re strike; 3 p. "Statement of Committee of AFL in Regard to the Communists and the Fur Workers Union"; and other misc.
- New York - Furriers Union, Joint Board, 1927-1928 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  letter from Local 1 re Vice-President Winnick's actions; between Gold and I. Wohl re a committee to investigate the financial standing of the Joint Board; 3 p. order of General Executive Board re immediate dissolution of New York Joint Board and delivering all funds and properties to Special Committee of the AFL; 3 p. "Official Information On Passing Events In Our Union From the International Fur Workers Union" by H. Begoon, General Secretary-Treasurer; 3 p. letter to officers from Begoon re the Communist threat of the Joint Board; broadside and misc.
- St. Paul - Joint Board, 1925-1939 (Box 29, Folder 14)
- St. Paul - Joint Board, 1940-1942 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  correspondence re the Joint Board's 25th Anniversary Celebration; and routine.
- Massachusetts - Boston - Leather Division Headquarters, 1941 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  January-May; letter, 4/21/41, re new charter issued to Local 215, Bristol, Pennsylvania; agreement; and routine.
- Massachusetts - Boston - Leather Division Headquarters, 1941 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  June-December; re charter issued for Local 220, St. Mary's; agreement; list of Leather organizers; and routine.
- Massachusetts - Boston - Leather Division Headquarters, 1942 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  January-June; routine.
- Massachusetts - Boston - Leather Division Headquarters, 1942-1951 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  routine and financial reports.
- Massachusetts - Boston - District Council 1, 1945-1954 (Box 29, Folder 20)
  correspondence re local's actions on wage increase, 1 day stoppage of leather plants, aid for war stricken people of Europe; letter and articles re President of Local 21, Peabody, being a Communist; 3 p. letter from Gold to William Dougherty (Peabody) re the A. C. Lawrence local problems; other correspondence re Local 21, A. C. Lawrence; union brief between Locals 20, 21, 22 and Massachusetts Leather Manufacturers Association; correspondence re members against merger with Meat Cutters; 2 p. "Statement by New England Members of the International Executive Board" re indictment of Gold; and routine.
- Midwest - District 4, 1945 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  January-June; extensive correspondence between Gold and Abe Feinglass, Midwest Regional Director re district activities especially the Chicago election and the need for organizers; reports on various cities in the district re negotiations and organizing drives.
- Midwest - District 4, 1945 (Box 29, Folder 22)
  July-November; correspondence between Gold and Abe Feinglass, Midwest Regional Director re district activities especially the Chicago election and the need for organizers; leaflets and broadsides re Chicago Luggage Workers; correspondence re District 4 Southern Sub-District concerning organizing, etc. in Louisiana, North Carolina and other southern states; map and list of companies in district.
- Midwest - District 4, 1942-1954 (Box 29, Folder 23)
  includes financial reports; re merger with Meat Cutters; to Gold from Abe Feinglass, Midwest Regional Director, re Credit Union of Local 96 and other financial and routine; support from various local members for Gold during his trial; raiding attacks by other unions; 3 p. letter from Gold in reply to letter of support form John Salfer, Local 360, discussing his indictment under Taft-Hartley Act, his beliefs, etc.; letter to Feinglass from Gold re Negro rights; and routine.
- Midwest - District 4, 1954 (Box 29, Folder 24)
  correspondence between Feinglass and Gold re Midwest District activities; 3 p. letter from Harold Shipiro, Manager, Local 38 (Detroit), re Shipiro's hearing and Gold's reply; re Gold's defense; handwritten report addressed to Feinglass re "Facts on the Florida Citrus Industry"; 2 p. resolutions adopted by Chicago Joint Board re support and admiration for B. Gold; letters of congratulations to Feinglass on becoming President of the union; and other routine.
- Midwest - District 4, 1954 (Box 29, Folder 25)
  letters of congratulation to Feinglass; 11/3/54 issue Daily Strike Bulletin, Local 833, Kohler; correspondence re negotiations and activities throughout district; report of District Conference; broadsides; and routine.
- Pennsylvania - Philadelphia - District Council 2, 1954-1955 (Box 29, Folder 26)
- North Carolina - District Council 5, 1954 (Box 29, Folder 27)
  correspondence and leaflets re organizing agricultural workers; report on southern locals; 4 p. mss. entitled "Our Way of Life - and Death" by Harry Koger, Chairman, Committee to Aid Migrant Workers; and routine.
- Pennsylvania - Williamsport - District Council 3, 1945-1953 (Box 29, Folder 28)
  by-laws of District 3; re stoppage in Franklin Tanning Co., Local 31; reports of negotiations and other activities throughout district; financial difficulties of the district; and routine.
- Pennsylvania - Williamsport - District Council 3, 1954-1955 (Box 29, Folder 29)
  NLRB legal document re Local 211 election; form letter to employees of Armour Leather Co. from Meat Cutters re organizing; list of officers; broadside; and routine.
- Wisconsin - District Office, 1945-1947 (Box 29, Folder 30)
  correspondence between Gold and Augustus Tomlinson, President, Leather Division, Wisconsin, re problems replacing organizers due to war, victory in New England, luggage workers in Chicago, district activities and routine.
- Leather Division Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 29, Folder 31)
  correspondence from various locals to Gold, voting on holiday, wage increase and work stoppage.
- Leather Division Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 29, Folder 32)
- Leather Division Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 29, Folder 33)
  re work stoppage in support of 30% wage increase and misc.
- Cultural - White Lake Lodge, 1953-1954 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  includes minutes of Resort Management Committee, 5/30/54; minutes of White Lake Lodge Committee, 6/54; routine financial, employment agency contracts, reservations.
- Gold, Ben - Trial Transcript, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  United States of America vs. Ben Gold, galley transcript of proceedings in U. S. District Court for the District of Columbia re affiliation with Communist Party.
- Gold, Ben - Trial Transcript, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 3)
- Gold, Ben - Trial Transcript, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 4)
- Gold, Ben - Trial Transcript, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 5)
- Gold, Ben - Trial Transcript, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 6)
- Gold, Ben - Trial - Court documents, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  includes briefs, lists of evidence, motion for dismissal, handwritten notes, affadavits.
- Gold, Ben - Trial - Court documents, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 8)
- Gold, Ben - Trial - Court documents, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 9)
- Gold, Ben - Trial - Court documents, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 10)
- Gold, Ben - Trial Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  letter to NLRB re compliance status of the International Fur and Leather Workers Union in view of Ben Gold's indictment, 9/8/53; form letter from Ben Gold to International Executive Board members, 1/12/54, re his being "frmed-up", lettersto Gold praising the union's work; form letters from the Trade Union Committee for the Defense of Ben Gold and contribution booklet; and routine.
- Gold - Trial - Bulletins #1-17, 1953-1954 (Box 30, Folder 12)
- Gold - Trial - Bulletins #1-17, 1953-1954 (Box 30, Folder 13)
- Gold - Trial Miscellaneous, 1953-1954 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  articles; handwritten notes; broadside; pamphlets; photo, B. Gold's statement on his resignation as President, etc.
- Gold - Trial Miscellaneous, 1953-1954 (Box 30, Folder 15)
- Gold, Ben - Trial - Related Case - Court documents, 1953 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  International Fur and Leather Workers Union vs. Guy Farmer, Chairman of the NLRB re the Board limiting the compliance status of the union because of Gold indictment.
- Grievances and decisions of the Conference Committee of the Fur Industry (Dr. Paul Abelson, Chairman), 1936-1940 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  includes company names, complaints and answers.
- Grievances and decisions of the Conference Committee of the Fur Industry (Dr. Paul Abelson, Chairman), 1936-1940 (Box 30, Folder 18)
- Grievances and decisions of the Conference Committee of the Fur Industry (Dr. Paul Abelson, Chairman), 1936-1940 (Box 30, Folder 19)
- Grievances and decisions of the Conference Committee of the Fur Industry (Dr. Paul Abelson, Chairman), 1936-1940 (Box 30, Folder 20)
- Grievances and decisions of the Conference Committee of the Fur Industry (Dr. Paul Abelson, Chairman), 1936-1940 (Box 30, Folder 21)
- Grievances and decisions of the Conference Committee of the Fur Industry (Dr. Paul Abelson, Chairman), 1936-1940 (Box 30, Folder 22)
- Grievances and decisions of the Conference Committee of the Fur Industry (Dr. Paul Abelson, Chairman), 1936-1940 (Box 30, Folder 23)
- Grievances, 1936-1938 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  1938 Strike, complaints and answers of grievances.
- Grievances, 1936-1938 (Box 30, Folder 25)
- Grievances, 1936-1938 (Box 30, Folder 26)
- Grievances, 1936-1938 (Box 30, Folder 27)
- Grievances, 1936-1938 (Box 30, Folder 28)
- Grievances, 1936-1938 (Box 31, Folder 1)
- Grievances, 1936-1938 (Box 31, Folder 2)
- Grievances, 1936-1938 (Box 31, Folder 3)
- Grievances, 1936-1938 (Box 31, Folder 4)
- Grievances, 1936-1938 (Box 31, Folder 5)
- McCarthy, Joseph - Trade Union Veterans Committee (Against), 1953-1954 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  correspondence re "Trial of Senator Joseph McCarthy.
- McCarthy, Joseph - Trade Union Veterans Committee (Against), 1953-1954 (Box 31, Folder 7)
- McCarthy, Joseph - Trade Union Veterans Committee (Against), 1953-1954 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  form letters.
- McCarthy, Joseph - Trade Union Veterans Committee (Against), 1953-1954 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  articles; news releases; pamphlet "Mandel vs. McCarthy", 1953, 23 p.; and misc.
- McCarthy, Joseph - Trade Union Veterans Committee (Against), 1953-1954 (Box 31, Folder 10)
- McCarthy, Joseph - Trade Union Veterans Committee (Against), 1953-1954 (Box 31, Folder 11)
- National Leather Workers Association, 1938 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  proceedings of the Fifth National Convention, Boston, Massachusetts, 4/29-5/2, unpaged, (1 vol.).
- Strike General, 1926 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  includes "Brief History of the Internal Dissention Among the Organized Fur Workers and Events Taking Place Before the Strike," unpaged, undated (photostatic copies).
- Strike - General - AFL Investigation, 1926 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  photostatic copies of AFL Investigation transcript, includes union demands, testimony of union officials, recommendations.
- Strike - General - AFL Investigation, 1926 (Box 31, Folder 15)
- Strike - General - AFL Investigation, 1926 (Box 31, Folder 16)
- Strike - application for settlement, 1938 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  correspondence from independent fur companies in New York City requesting information on settling strike individually.
- Strike Settlement, 1938 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  correspondence from companies requesting individual settlements marked "settled"; photograph; signed agreement between J. Cohen and Son Fur Co. and Fur Merchants Employees Union of the International Fur Workers Union 8/16/38-8/16/39; handwritten notes; an envelope with typed notes on day to day activities of a Mr. G. and Miss B.
- Strike Settlement, 1938 (Box 31, Folder 19)
- United Leather Workers International Union (ULWIU), 1942 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  Constitution, July 1, 40 p.
- ULWIU, Local 33 minutebook, 1933-1937 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  bound volume.
- ULWIU, Local 33, 1933-1937 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  correspondence between W. O. Mulholland, President, Local 33, A. L. Malain, Assistant Secretary-Treasurer, and William E. Bryan, President, ULWIU, re Franklin Tanning Co. wage rates amd strike in May 1934; correspondence with National Labor Board re strike and attempt to destroy the local at Franklin Tanning Co.; and routine correspondence.
- ULWIU, Local 33, 1933-1937 (Box 31, Folder 23)
- ULWIU, Local 33, 1933-1937 (Box 31, Folder 24)
- ULWIU, Local 33, 1933-1937 (Box 31, Folder 25)
- ULWIU, Local 33, 1933-1937 (Box 31, Folder 26)
- ULWIU, Local 33, 1933-1937 (Box 31, Folder 27)
- ULWIU, Local 33 Miscellaneous (Box 31, Folder 28)
  broadsides; seniority list; form letter; "Statement of Facts Regarding Complaints" Franklin Tanning Co. vs. Local 33; and misc.
- ULWIU, Local 34, 1933-1935 (Box 31, Folder 29)
  correspondence with the International Union re negotiations with J. K. Mosser Co.; and routine.
- ULWIU, Local 72, 1937 (Box 31, Folder 30)
  letter re suspension of payments to the International Union sent to another local encouraging them to do the same.
- ULWIU, Local 75, 1937 (Box 31, Folder 31)
- ULWIU, Local 120, 1947 (Box 31, Folder 32)
  form letter; broadsides.
- ULWIU, 1933-1937 (Box 31, Folder 33)
  circulars, reports, includes financial statements.
- ULWIU, 1933-1937 (Box 31, Folder 34)
- ULWIU Miscellaneous, 1935-1936 (Box 31, Folder 35)
  due book; application cards; schedule of wages for Massachusetts Tannery Workers, 1935; agreement between ULWIU, Local 31 and International Shoe Co., St. Louis, Missouri, 1946.
- Circulars, Broadsides, etc., 1928-1947 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  includes petitions, convention credentials, circulars, broadsides, strike calls, applications for affiliation, etc.
- Clippings, 1946-1945 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  English and Yiddish.
- Clippings, 1946-1945 (Box 32, Folder 3)
- Publications, 1941 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  includes scattered issues of periodicals and newsletters; "Digest of Two Federal Cases Against Leaders of the IFLWU," no date, 5 p.; "The Rise and Decline of America's First and Oldest Industry" by A. Hollander and Son, Inc., no date, 13 p.; "Jubilee Journals" issued at 25th and 50th anniversary of Furriers International Council of New York; "Ten Minutes Overtime," a play by Mark Hess, 1941, 28 p.
- Publications, 1941 (Box 32, Folder 5)
- Publications, 1941 (Box 32, Folder 6)
- Publications, 1941 (Box 32, Folder 7)
- Form letters, 1937-1940 (Box 32, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous, 1944 (Box 32, Folder 9)